Guide to the United Scenic Artists Records WAG.065
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Scenic Artists Records
1897-1984, (Bulk 1912-1964)
1912-1964
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
United Scenic Artists. Local USA 829
WAG.065
6 Linear Feet (8 boxes)
The United Scenic Artists (USA), now Local USA 829 of the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees, is the labor union of scenic artists and designers in the theatrical and entertainment industries nation-wide, but with a heavy concentration of members in the New York metropolitan area. The collection includes by-laws, constitutions, minutes, correspondence, financial records, and legal documents. Also included are files on World War II-era activities of the union, on individual members and their work, and on the union's stringent entrance examinations.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by the United Scenic Artists, Local 829, in 1988. The accession number associated with this gift is 1988.003.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
United Scenic Artists is a labor union representing designers and artists in the theater, opera, ballet, motion picture, television, and industrial exhibition industries. It originated as the United Scenic Artists Association and received its charter from the American Federation of Labor in 1918 as Local 829, an autonomous local of the Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades. The union's main purposes were to safeguard and maintain the high standards of the member crafts and to fight unfair working conditions.
The union represents an array of creative professions, and has expanded and adapted its classifications to conform to changes in the entertainment industry. In the 1920s, when scenic designers and scenic artists began to be differentiated from each other, and one artist was no longer responsible for the various facets of stage design, the union accommodated to these changes. In the following decades the union continued revising its classification system to include studio shopmen, costume and lighting designers, display and panorama artists, muralists, and most recently, computer and projection artists.
USA Local 829 has also had a notable political history. During the 1920s, the local was active in a variety of AFL campaigns; many of its members participated in a 1922 strike in Albany to defeat the Duell-Miller Bill, which proposed to outlaw strikes and lockouts, thereby enforcing binding arbitration on labor disputes. In the early 1940s, the union wholeheartedly supported the war effort, and many members left the entertainment industry altogether for the war industries. Others were active in the Theatre Artists and Designers War Service, offering their labor to patriotic parades and pageants, and decorating windows for Russian War Relief.
Jurisdictional Disputes were commonplace for the USA, especially during the period when television and film were burgeoning industries. Particularly intense disputes arose between the union and locals of the International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) in the 1940s. Most notable of these confrontations was a 1948-1949 strike in Hollywood, which resulted in the USA losing jurisdiction over several categories of scenic artists in California to IATSE; even today, USA Local 829 members in California consist solely of theater designers. During the 1940s and 50s the television industry was growing rapidly as well, and Local 829 moved quickly to develop and secure its jurisdiction. Negotiations with major television networks were complicated and intense, resulting in several strikes during the 40s and 50s. In the 1960s and 70s, specialized contracts with the networks, commercial producers, and motion picture studios were developed to reflect the growth of these sectors.
Throughout the 1980s and the 1990s, USA Local 892 continued to go through structural and jurisdictional changes. In 1983, a group of West Coast designers chose to affiliate with the union, which opened a Los Angeles office to serve them. In March of 1990, a merger with the International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades (IBPAT), Local 350 in Chicago was effected and thereby jurisdiction was gained throughout the United States. However, in 1999 the union voted to disaffiliate with the IBPAT and re-affiliate with the IATSE, acquiring the new name, United Scenic Artists, Local USA 829, IATSE.
Scope and Content Note
Series I: Minutes, 1912-1975, is comprised of microfilmed executive board and membership meeting minutes on microfilm and in bound volumes, with the earliest dating to September 1912 with the development with the United Scenic Artists Association of America. The bound volumes include minutes covering 1912-1924. A volume, "Book B," that would have covered the years 1920-1922, appears to be missing. Most early meetings are identified only as "regular" meetings of officers; minutes of meetings of committees convened for special purposes are occasionally included as well. This series also includes USA Executive Board minutes from 1930-1953. Researchers must use microfilm when available.
Series II: By-Laws and Constitutions, 1926-1935; 1970, includes By-Laws, Constitutions, and Working Rules from 1926, 1932, and 1934. This series also contains Constitutions with proposed revisions from 1935 and 1970.
Series III: General Files, 1897-1984, is comprised of subject files arranged alphabetically by topic or organization, and then chronologically within each topic or organization. This series provides a broad overview of USA's early history, defining membership and relationships with related and governing unions. Files include contract negotiations and agreements, bound financial records from 1912-1913, the Federal Theatre Project, membership correspondence, material on committees and documentation of membership classifications. Files pertaining to organizations affiliated with the USA can also be found in this series. The extensive Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers (BPDPA, now the International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades) and International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employees (IATSE) correspondence files demonstrate the sometimes tumultuous relationships between the affiliated performing arts unions due to jurisdictional disputes. The Costume Designers files include a record of specific membership requirements to maintain good standing in this section of the USA, as well as documentation of fines for non-attendance. USA's involvement in World War II is represented in the government correspondence, which includes information about the Civil Service Commission and camouflage activities, and Artists for Victory files.
Series IV: Oversized Material, 1930-1972. These miscellaneous materials include records of a dispute between Waldo Angelo and Florentz Klotz regarding Harold Prince's "Follies" (1971-1972) and diorama and display workers agreements from 1957. Also included in Series IV is a large bound scrapbook of theatrical clippings, pictures, playbills, and reviews from the 1930s and 1940s; this scrapbook is not arranged chronologically.
Arrangement
Series I and II are arranged chronologically; series III and IV are arranged alphabetically.
The files are grouped into 4 series:
Missing Title
I, Minutes, 1912-1953
II, By-Laws and Constitutions, 1926-1970
III, General Files, 1897-1984
IV, Oversized Materials, 1930-1972
Separated Material
Photographs, sketches, and watercolors have been separated to the Non-Print Department of the Tamiment Library.
These items were reintegrated into the original collection May 2018.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Due to the fragile nature of the original materials, researchers must use the microfilmed version of Series I: Minutes - Subseries I.A; microfilm call number is R7431.
Memorandums.; Examinations (documents); Clippings (information artifacts); Reports.; Motion picture industry |x Employees |x Labor unions |z United States.; New York (N.Y.); Set designers |z United States.; Motion pictures |z United States |x History.; Television |z United States |x History.; Theater -- United States -- History.; Theaters |z United States |x Employees.; Theaters |x Stage-setting and scenery |x History.; Bylaws (administrative records).; Constitutions.; Minutes (administrative records); Legal documents.; Correspondence.; Financial records; United Scenic Artists. Local USA 829; International Brotherhood of Painters and Allied Trades; National Broadcasting Company; International Alliance of Theatrical Stage Employes, Moving Picture Technicians, Artists and Allied Crafts of the United States and Canada; League of New York Theatres; Theatre Artists and Designers War Service (U.S.); United Scenic Artists. Local USA 829
- Series I: Minutes, 1912-1975
  - Subseries I:A: Microfilm, 1918-1975
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1918-1922 (Film R-7431, Reel 1)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1923-1926 (Film R-7431, Reel 2)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1927-1930 (Film R-7431, Reel 3)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1931-1933 (Film R-7431, Reel 4)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1934-1936 (Film R-7431, Reel 5)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1937-1939 (Film R-7431, Reel 6)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1940-1941 (Film R-7431, Reel 7)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1942-1944 (Film R-7431, Reel 8)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1945-1949 (Film R-7431, Reel 9)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1950-1955 (Film R-7431, Reel 10)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1956-1963 (Film R-7431, Reel 11)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1965-1967 (Film R-7431, Reel 12)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1968-1970 (Film R-7431, Reel 13)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1971-1973 (Film R-7431, Reel 14)
    - Minutes: Executive Board and Membership Meetings, 1974-1975 (Film R-7431, Reel 15)
    - Minutes: Costume Associates, 1954-1962 (Film R-7431, Reel 15)
  - Subseries I:B: Paper, 1912-1953
    - Minutes, Sep 1912-Oct 1919 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minutes (bound ledger book), Dec 1912-May 1917 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Minutes (inserts from ledger book in folder 2), 1916-1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Minutes (bound volume), Jul 1918-Aug 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Minutes (bound volume), Aug 1918-1920 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Minutes (bound volume labeled "Record" and Book "C"), 1922-1924 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Minutes: Executive Board, 1930-1953 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Series II: By-Laws and Constitutions, 1926-1935; 1970
  - By-Laws, Constitution, and Working Rules, 1926, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - By-Laws, Strike Clause and Working Rules, undated, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Constitution: Proposed Revisions, 1935 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Constitution: Proposed Revisions, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Series III: General Files, 1897-1984
  - Actors' Equity, 1919-1948 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Alien Issues: Arne Lundborg Correspondence, Mar 1952-May 1952 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Alien Issues: Correspondence regarding non-U.S. workers, Dec 1935-Apr 1940 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Alien Issues: Importation of Foreign Sets and Costumes, Mar 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Almanac, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - American Guild of Variety Artists, 1940-1943 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Andrews v. Percival, Oct 1952-Sep 1936 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Artists for Victory, USA, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Association of Theatrical Agents and Managers, 1944-1949 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Backdrops, Inc., 1950-1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Brooks Costume Company: Correspondence, Feb 1936-Sep 1944 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Brooks Costume Company: Correspondence, Membership Applications, and IATSE Membership, Nov 1952 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Brotherhood of Painters, Decorators and Paperhangers of America (BPDPA): Correspondence, 1915, 1918-1920 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, 1920-1923 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Feb 1926-May 1927 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jun 1927 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jul 1927 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1928-Dec 1928 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1929-Nov 1929 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1930-Dec 1930 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1931-Dec 1931 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1932-Dec 1932 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1933-Dec 1933 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1934-Dec 1934 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Feb 1935-Dec 1935 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Mar 1936-Dec 1936 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1937-Dec 1937 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Mar 1938-Sep 1938 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Feb 1939-Oct 1939 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Mar 1940-Dec 1940 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1941-Dec 1941 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1942-Nov 1942 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Apr 1943-Dec 1943 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1944-Jul 1950 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Feb 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jan 1952-Nov 1954 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Feb 1955-Dec 1957 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Jun 1961-Dec 1963 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - BPDPA: Correspondence, Aug 1964-Oct 1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - BPDPA: Local 230 (New York Sign Writers), By-Laws and Rules, undated (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - BPDPA: Local 230: Display and Exposition Agreement, 1930-1939 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - BPDPA: Local 350 (Chicago): Correspondence, 1932-1936, Oct 1947-Oct 1953 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - BPDPA: Local 350 (Chicago): Correspondence, Jan 1954-Jul 1958 (Box 3, Folder 47)
  - BPDPA: National Joint Board Decisions, 1962, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - BPDPA: Report of Paint Spraying Fact Finding Commission, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 49)
  - Building and Construction Trades Council: Correspondence, Jun 1940-Apr 1956 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Camp Shows, Inc., Nov 1941-Jan 1942 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Casey, Pat (Producer's Committee), Jan 1944 (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Celebrity Service, Inc., 1944-1948 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Central Trades and Labor Council, Jan 1935-Apr 1961 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Chemical Bank and Trust Company, Jun 1927-Oct 1948 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Clippings, 1912-1966 (Box 3, Folder 56)
  - Combined Amusement Crafts: "By-Laws and Directory", undated (Box 3, Folder 57)
  - Combined Theatrical and Amusement Crafts Council, Nov 1924-Dec 1952 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Committee on Investigation: Transcript of Meeting Proceedings, Nov 1934 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Contracts and Agreements, 1910-1930 (Box 3, Folder 60)
  - Contracts and Agreements, Apr 1941-Dec 1942 (Box 3, Folder 61)
  - Contracts and Agreements, 1943-1957 (Box 3, Folder 62)
  - Contracts and Agreements, 1960-1968 (Box 3, Folder 63)
  - Correspondence, 1916-1919 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1921-1931 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1939 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1941-1966 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1918, 1920-1929 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1930-1932 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1933-1934 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1935-1942 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1943-1947 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Members, 1949-1968 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, Sep 1945-Dec 1946 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, Jan 1947-Oct 1948 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, Mar 1949-Dec 1951 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, Feb 1952-Sep 1952 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, Oct 1952-Dec 1952 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, Jan 1953-Dec 1953 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Costume Designers: Correspondence, Meetings and Minutes, 1954-1958, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Costume Shops: Outgoing Correspondence, 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Designer's Fees, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Detroit: Civic Light Opera Association, Dec 1943 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Diorama and Display Workers: Attendance, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Diorama and Display Workers: Correspondence, Jul 1941-Nov 1941 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Diorama and Display Workers: Correspondence, Sep 1945-Feb 1948 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Diorama and Display Workers: Correspondence, 1954-1957, 1961-1963 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Diorama and Display Workers: Minutes, 1952-1957 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Diorama and Display Workers: Minutes, 1958-1967 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Doyle, John, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dreyfuss, Henry v. Myron Fagan, 1924-1929 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dues: Extensions Granted, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Educational Committee, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Eisele, Lou, 1945-1947 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Elections and Legislation, 1924, 1927-1939 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Elections and Legislation, Apr 1940-Jul 1940 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Elections and Legislation, Aug 1940-Feb 1941 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Elections and Legislation, Mar 1941-Dec 1942 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Elections and Legislation, Feb 1943-1957 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater Foundation: Theater of the Deaf Proposal, 1962-1964 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Exam, undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Examining Board, 1937-1953 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Exhibit Producers and Design Association Inc: Correspondence (includes BPDPA), Dec 1937-Feb 1939 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Exhibition: "Scenic Designers Offstage", 1960-1962 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Falk, Jacob A. (Auditor), 1942-1943, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Federal Theatre Project, 1935-1939 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Ferretti, Andrea, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Film Producers Association: Correspondence and Contracts, Mar 1962-Dec 1962 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Film Producers Association: Correspondence and Contracts, 1963-1969 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Film Technicians (Motion Picture Industry, Local No.669): "Constitution and By-Laws", undated (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Financial Records: Meeting receipts, disbursements, initiation fees and dues book (bound volume), 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Financial Records: Management initiation and dues book (bound volume), 1912-1913 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Financial Records: Treasurer's Report and Receipts, 1918-1920 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Gallagher, William, Jan 1940-May 1941 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Government: Correspondence, 1940-1945 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Government: Correspondence (Camouflage), 1941 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Government: Correspondence (Civil Service Commission), Dec 1940-Sep 1942 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Government: Social Security Pamphlets, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Group Insurance, 1927-1941 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - History (United Scenic Artists), Sep 1967 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - IATSE: Correspondence (includes BPDPA), Oct 1918-Apr 1919 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - IATSE: Correspondence (includes BPDPA), May 1919-Apr 1920 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - IATSE: Correspondence (includes Actors' Equity), Jan 1921-Oct 1924 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Jan 1925-Dec 1926 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Jan 1927-Nov 1927 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Jan 1928-Dec 1928 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Feb 1929-Dec 1929 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Jan 1930-Dec 1931 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Jan 1932-Dec 1933 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Feb 1934-Aug 1934 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Sep 1934-Mar 1939 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - IATSE: Correspondence, Feb 1940-Mar 1951 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - IATSE, Local 847: Correspondence, Nov 1958 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - IATSE: Proceedings of 29th Convention, Detroit, Jun 1928 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - IATSE: Scenic Artists Local 816 (Hollywood), 1952-1955 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Jam Handy Organization: Correspondence, Dec 1945 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Johnson, Wood & Co. CPA: Correspondence, Apr 1927-May 1942 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Johnson, Wood & Co. CPA: Financial Statements, 1938-1940 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Karnholt, Rudy: Business Representative Correspondence, Mar 1948-Nov 1952 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - League of New York Theatres: Agreements, 1984-1984 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - League of New York Theatres: Correspondence, Aug 1931-Mar 1932 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - League of New York Theatres: Correspondence, Apr 1932-Sep 1939 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - League of New York Theatres: Correspondence, Apr 1940-Dec 1952 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority: Correspondence, Dec 1933-Jun 1934 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority (National Legitimate Theatre Committee): Minutes, Aug 1933-Sep 1933 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority (National Legitimate Theatre Committee): Minutes, Sep 1933-Dec 1933 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority: Minutes, Jan 1934-Feb 1934 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority: Minutes, Mar 1934-Jun 1934 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority: Minutes, Aug 1934-Oct 1934 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Legitimate Theatre Code Authority: Minutes, Nov 1934-Jun 1935 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Lighting Designer's Committee, Feb 1962-Jun 1963 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Litigation: Banton vs. Wolper (settlement), 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Local 235 (Hollywood): Minutes, Mar 1932-Apr 1933 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Local 235 (Hollywood): Minutes, May 1933-Jan 1934 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Make-Up Artists: Examination, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Meeting Notices, 1966-1971 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Members: "Obligation" forms, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Membership applications, 1919-1950, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Membership lists, 1918-1919, 1927, 1931-1932 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Mielziner, Jo, undated (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Motion Picture: Contracts, Mar 1956-Aug 1956 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Motion Picture: Contracts, 1957-1966 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Motion Picture: Correspondence, Apr 1947-Aug 1962 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Motion Picture Production Unions Salute to Mayor John V. Lindsay: Program and Seating List, Sep 1968 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 1-118, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 119-240, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 241-425, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 426-466, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 467-629, 1967 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 630-802, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 803-921, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), pp. 922-1026, includes summary, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - NBC v. USA (Arbitration), Award, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - National Scenic Artists Conferences, Mar 1928-Aug 1929 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - National Scenic Artists Conferences, Apr 1930-Oct 1930 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - National Scenic Artists Conferences, Jan 1932-Apr 1936 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Notices: Membership, Dec 1942-Dec 1943 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Notices: Membership, 1944-1950, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Officers and Members Lists, 1915, 1946 (Box 7, Folder 19)